<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Mikołaj Słupiński's Blog - Mikołaj Słupiński</title><link>http://nerd911.github.io/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 23:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><item><title>[En] My top 5 machine learning books available for free</title><link>http://nerd911.github.io/2018_09_14_interesting_books.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Nowadays the number of free resources available on Internet is overwhelming.
There are many more free books than one can read.
Therefore, I created a short list consisting of the most valuable publications by my reckoning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;An Introduction to Statistical Learning with Applications in R&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book is unquestionable classic on the subject of machine learning.
It begins with linear regression and statistics, then moves on to more advanced linear models.
It also covers the topic of SVM, PCA and clustering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find it on &lt;a href="http://www-bcf.usc.edu/~gareth/ISL/"&gt;this site.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Neural Networks and Deep Learning&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's not a conventional book, because it's in the form of fully responsive website.
It covers the topic of neural networks and deep learning in an unconventional manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book explains a lot of mathematical concepts connected with the topic of artificial neural network in easy way.
The author created a lot of interesting interactive examples in javascript. &lt;a href="http://michaelnielsen.org/"&gt;Michael Nielsen&lt;/a&gt; did a great job, providing this publication with lots of exercises and problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read it &lt;a href="http://neuralnetworksanddeeplearning.com/"&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;R Notes for Professionals&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is great book for learning R for somebody who is familiar with programming.
The book doesn't have exercises for the reader, but uses a lot of examples.
It's not for somebody, who isn't familiar with programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://books.goalkicker.com/RBook/"&gt;Here's&lt;/a&gt; the download page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Python Notes for Professionals&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's mostly the same as the previous book, but I thought that it deserves separate paragraph. You can download it &lt;a href="https://books.goalkicker.com/PythonBook/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't forget to check out the rest of the books in &lt;a href="https://books.goalkicker.com/"&gt;the whole series.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Dive into Python 3&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as I'm concerned this is the best book to begin adventure with Python.
This book is easy to read and full of examples.
It provides the reader with all the crucial knowledge, byt doesn't overload him with too much information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get it &lt;a href="http://www.diveintopython3.net/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what are your favorite resources?
Share them in the comments.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mikołaj Słupiński</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 23:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:nerd911.github.io,2018-09-14:/2018_09_14_interesting_books.html</guid><category>cs</category><category>books</category><category>python</category><category>machine learning</category><category>r</category><category>free</category><category>resources</category><category>en</category></item><item><title>[En] Hello everyone</title><link>http://nerd911.github.io/2018_09_14_hello.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;DISCLAIMER&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I'm not native English speaker so if you find any errors be more than a welcome to send me a message about it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi everyone!
My name is Mikołaj Słupiński.
I am pursuing a master's degree both in Mathematics and Computer Science at University of Wrocław.
My main interests right now are machine learning and statistics.
My non science-related hobbies include gym and male fashion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to start a technical blog, in order to better understand some more complicated topics.
To be honest, I really doubt that I can cover valuable topics better than other online resources.
I treat this blog merely as a new way to self improvement, not only in my computer science understanding and but also in English usage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will publish in English as well as in Polish, because in my opinion there is not enough widely available Polish materials covering the most complicated topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you ever find any errors (especially grammatical ones) don't hesitate to mail me. I don't have a proofreader, so all help would be appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you will find materials posted here valuable and I wish you pleasant reading.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mikołaj Słupiński</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 22:50:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:nerd911.github.io,2018-09-14:/2018_09_14_hello.html</guid><category>welcome</category><category>misc</category></item></channel></rss>